James Ryan

james4165@hotmail.com Mobile Ph: 0430 710 408 jamesryan.azurewebsites.net

I have 5 years of programming experience including 1.5 years of web programming. My education is as a Civil Engineer though I am very interested in making a career change to software development.

Have a look at my portfolio for examples of my experience: jamesryan.azurewebsites.net

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2013 to Nov 2015 Graduate Civil Engineer (Full-Time)

Real Serious Games

Key Accomplishments:

- Use of Microsoft Excel for manipulating large volumnes of construction schedule data and other data from companies such as Leightons, Thiess and Lend Lease
- Programming of various tools used in the office using C#, WPF and VBA and communicating regularly with programmers
- Providing mockup drawings for modifications to 3D Models
- QA of software
- Communicating construction drawings to 3D modelers

2011 to 2013 Trainee Structural Engineer (Full-Time)

NBR Australia

Key Accomplishments:

- Carried out structural design of cold-formed steel portal frame buildings and various types of residential buildings.
- Structural drafting of various commercial and industrial portal frame buildings and residential homes and associated detail drawings
- Developed in-house structural engineering software used for analysing loads and calculating bracing, member and connection requirements for portal frame buildings
- Development of 3D portal frame model and load generation software in Excel/VBA using Multiframe Automation.
- Used many different Australian Standards and product manuals
- Other duties such as general administration and document handling/organisation

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2009 to 2013 Bachelor of Engineering majoring in Civil and Construction

Queensland University of Technology

2005 to 2006 **Diploma of Mechanical Engineering**

Moreton Institute of TAFE

Resume: James Ryan

Extra Curricular Achievements

- Winner of 2011 Baulderstone National Icons design competition
 - 1st place out of over 150 entries nation wide
 - Winning entry consisted of conceptual redesign of the Story Bridge and 700 word report
- Designed and published two Android applications on Google Play
 - "EasyBeam" a structural engineering application
 - "Where in the World", a Google map and streetview based guessing game

Programming Skills

I have been programming on my own personal projects and at previous workplaces for almost 5 years and have experience with :

- C# and WPF
- Java for Android
- Node.js, html, sass/css, javascript, SQL Server, Azure Websites, Backbone.js. Also some PHP and Laravel
- Very proficient with Microsoft Excel and VBA, and knowledge of Microsoft Word
- Some knowledge of R for statisical analysis

Interests

- Computers & Programming(Web, C#, VBA)
- Sharemarket

- Video Games
- Making guitar/electronic songs

REFEREES

Dr Greg Darcy

NBR Australia

Ph: 0421 671 454

Rod Etto

Etto Designs and Drafting

Ph: 0411 564 529

Professor Tommy Chan

Queensland University of Technology (QUT)

tommy.chan@gut.edu.au

Resume: James Ryan